Contact

repairist@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/remplant (LinkedIn) github.com/RyanGoslingsBugle (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Python MySQL Web Analytics

Languages

German (Elementary)
English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

JavaScript Road Trip Part 3
Rails for Zombies Redux
JavaScript Road Trip Part 2
Try jQuery
Try Laravel

Honors-Awards

University Medal

Richard Plant

PhD Student at Edinburgh Napier University Edinburgh

Summary

PhD student at Edinburgh Napier University in the Computing department, researching machine leaning and natural language processing technologies. Research interests include online media, public safety, privacy and data-driven decision making.

Previously a freelance web developer providing full-stack development project services. Former journalist, editor, manager, video news editor.

Technology focuses include Python, Java, Machine Learning, and database systems.

Experience

Edinburgh Napier University
Researcher PHD Student
March 2020 - Present (1 year 5 months)
Edinburgh, Scotland, United Kingdom

Researching machine learning technologies with a focus on privacy, member of the Nature-Inspired Intelligent Systems group. Also involved in teaching and student support.

Freelance

Web Developer April 2016 - March 2020 (4 years)

Edinburgh, United Kingdom

Freelance web developer, working on full-stack applications for various clients. My key focus is identifying and serving the needs of businesses and individuals by choosing the best technologies and platforms for their particular use-cases, and providing top-class development, maintenance, documentation, training and support.

Key foci:

- * MEAN Stack (MySQL, Express, Angular, NodeJS)
- * Database Management
- * RESTful services
- * Client application development (C#/Visual Basic)
- * Change management and deployment

I can also provide ongoing support on a contract basis, as well as acting as a point of contact with third-party providers including hosting and services providers, CDNs and other developers.

Current technical interests:

- * Ruby/Rails
- * Java
- * Mobile application development

Ruptly

3 years 3 months

Web Administrator

August 2014 - March 2016 (1 year 8 months)

Managing the development, upgrading and day-to-day maintenance of the company's website, database and related technical systems. Acting as contact coordinator between in-house technical staff, contract developers, third-party suppliers, newsroom managers and end-users. Responsible for generation of training documentation, workflow optimisation and planning for further developments in digital media.

Key responsibilities:

- * Tracking and monitoring tasks, issues, risks, project milestones and related reporting
- * Triage on incoming tickets
- * JIRA management
- * In-house tool development (C#/ASP.NET/VBASIC/Javascript/Python/Shell scripting)
- * DB administration (MySQL/RDS)
- * 24 hour on-call support including crisis resolution and mitigation

Output Editor

January 2013 - August 2014 (1 year 8 months)

I am in a position of primary responsibility for the output of the newsroom team during my shift. I control the style guide, editing practices, script and shot lists, and the factual accuracy of all packages leaving the office to our websites, clients and other outlets. I coordinate contact between my team of broadcast journalists and the field producers who feed them content to be edited, as well as assigning responsibilities and priorities. I also act as the point of contact with Output for the Intake Editor and Editor of the Day.

Citizen Game

News Editor

August 2011 - August 2013 (2 years 1 month)

I am heavily involved in the relaunch of this enthusiast community for UK and Irish video gaming fans. I coordinate news coverage, provide features, interviews and blog content and ideas, in addition to creating traditional reviews. I have built up a substantial PR contact list, and covered events including the Eurogamer Expo. I have been involved with podcast and video production.

Gameforge

PR Manager UK

May 2012 - November 2012 (7 months)

I handle UK and English-language press and public relations for German games publisher Gameforge. A serious force in European gaming, Frogster boasts titles such as TERA, RaiderZ, Runes of Magic and Aion amongst its stable of exciting and immersive online gaming experiences.

IDG Communications UK

2 years 9 months

Lead Content Manager

January 2011 - April 2012 (1 year 4 months)

I am responsible for the day-to-day running of the Computerworld UK and Techworld B2B websites, working with the editor to identify, proof and edit suitable content from commissioned authors and other publications in the IDG group. I also research and write my own news, features, reviews and blog posts. Working with a small team, I am responsible for keeping the B2B style guide updated, setting down social media and SEO policy and training journalists. This includes running Twitter, Facebook and LinkedIn profiles as well as responsibility for editorial email newsletters. Also filming, producing and editing video news bulletins, interviews and other content.

Junior Content Manager August 2009 - January 2011 (1 year 6 months)

Responsible for day to day running of several large B2B technology websites, sub-editing content, writing stories and blogs, producing marketing copy, designing and sending newsletters, promoting sites via social media.

Metia

Junior Writer November 2008 - April 2009 (6 months)

I was employed by this innovative technology-focused marketing agency to produce outstanding copy for their marketing campaigns. Working for big players in the fields of Information Technology, Telecommunications, Logistics and Financial Services, the editorial team produces a range of customer evidence materials and marketing collateral. This position demands a painstaking attention to detail, excellent self-editing skills and creative talent.

Education

Edinburgh Napier University

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Computer Science · (2020 - 2023)

Edinburgh Napier University

MSc Computing, Computing (2017 - 2019)

The Manchester Metropolitan University BA English, English · (2005 - 2008)

James Gillespies High School (1995 - 2001)